Yashar Heydari

Senior Software Engineer

98-912 425 4290



in http://www.linkedin.com/in/yasharheydari

Tehran, Iran

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated Senior Software Engineer with 10+ years of experience in enterprise software solutions development for Banking and Fintech industries using C#, Java, and Oracle DB. Proven achievements in Object-Oriented Programming, OO Analysis and Design, Database Design and programming, Development of Enterprise Applications, Team leadership, Agile Process and Principles, and Big-data. Keen to learn with Can-do attitude, analysis ability, and strong problem-solving capability.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer/Architect

Aug. 2020 - Present

Tosan (Banking and Payment Solution Provider) • Tehran, Iran

Promoted to System Engineer/Architect role, being in charge of technology, business and architecture improvements as well as process and Software Production Lifecycle transformations.

- Raised attention towards SAFe framework in enterprise level, investigating the production lifecycle process in order to adapt required transformations.
- Co-led implementation of DevOps pipeline, CI\CD, and migration to BitBucket and Bamboo.
- Initiated and held ongoing Architecture and Design reviews, capturing bottlenecks and proposing improvements, and encouraging teams for continuous improvements.

Senior Software Engineer

Jan. 2016- Aug. 2020

Tosan (Banking and Payment Solution Provider) • Tehran, Iran

Promoted to Senior Software Development Lead, being in charge of 50+ technical and business people. Improved process and lifecycle of enterprise application development and maintenance by 30%, engaging and motivating developers, hiring enthusiastic programmers, and putting high priority on training.

- Supervised the software production, dealing with detailed architecture and design decisions as well as requirements developments.
- Planned and performed over 70,000 hours of schedule to fulfill 500+ customer requests annually.
- Accomplished 5 Big-data migration projects (with Billions of transactions) from legacy systems to modern banking solutions.
- Improved architecture, design, and performance of enterprise software products by 40% in Java EE (EJB 3.0 and OpenJPA), C#.Net, as well as Oracle scripts.
- Performed Software Development Process transformations (Agile/Scrum, TDD, Unit-Testing, codereview, etc.), achieving 10% of improvement.

Senior Software Engineer

Jul. 2010 - Jan. 2016

Tosan (Banking and Payment Solution Provider) • Tehran, Iran

Recruited as a Senior Software Engineer and Team-lead, developing and supervising a team of 7 developers. In charge of planning, technical quality and business conformity of implementations as well as code-review, problem-solving, and support.

- Played a key role in the implementation and maintenance of banking software solutions. Designed,
 Developed, and Technically Supported 1+ million Lines of Code.
- Produced and technically supported 20+ core banking modules (e.g. Deposit, Checks, Interest, etc.) using C#.Net, Java EE, and Oracle Database.
- Developed and performed 3 data migration projects, converting data from bank legacy systems to fresh banking solutions via PL/SQL modules.
- Participated in countless design and code reviews leading up to 45% performance improvements in both Java back-end services and client-side C#.Net WPF application.

Software Developer

Apr. 2008 - Jul. 2010

Freelancer • Tehran, Iran

- Built a full-functioning solution to restrain USB devices connected to 1000+ PCs in large organizations using Microsoft Visual C++.
- Customized windows logon DLL library, handling all USB ports and hubs via VC++ and win API.
- Developed a full-functioning educational staff and enrollment management system for a charity organization

Full-Stack VC++ Developer

Jan. 2006 – Mar. 2008

Kishware Co. • Tehran, Iran

- Implemented business capabilities in variety of modules using VC++ and Oracle for 10+ banks both on centralized and distributed environments.
- \bullet $\;$ Improved scalability and stability of the product by 20 % for large-scale banks.

EDUCATION

Master's degree in Software Engineering

2004-2007

Amirkabir University of Technology - Tehran Polytechnic • Tehran, Iran

Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering

2000-2004

Islamic Azad University • Tehran, Iran

Associate's degree in Computer Software

1998-2001

Shamsipour Technical and Vocational College • Tehran, Iran

SKILLS

- (10+ years): C#.Net, Java SE, Oracle, PL\SQL, TFS, NHibernate, WPF, WCF, VSS, SVN, TFS, RUP, VC++
- (6+ years): Scrum, Agile, Java EE, EJB 3.0, Open-JPA, TDD, CI/CD, Restful, Web API, .Net Remoting, Design Patterns, Web Services, ASP.Net MVC
- (Ongoing): Angular 9, Typescript, Web Frameworks, ASP.Net Core, and Clean Architecture
- Effective Communication Skills
- Team Player and Self-Awareness
- Critical Thinking and High Emotional Intelligence

LANGUAGES

English	Persian	Turkish\Azerbaijani
Advanced	Native	Fluent